# **Muhammad Alyan**

🗣 Islamabad, Pakistan 🗳 alyan0332@gmail.com 🔲 03333511136 🛅 in/alyan-hanif-2542b11ba 🕥 github.com/MuhammadAlyan1

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Fullstack Developer with 1 year of industry experience in MERN stack development. Dedicated to writing clean, maintainable code that adheres to industry best practices. I am committed to lifelong learning and staying updated with industry trends.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Fullstack Developer**

Usquare Solutions

January 2024 - Present, Islamabad

- Migrate ReactJS application from Mantine and JavaScript to a NextJS application using TailwindCSS and TypeScript.
- · Drive efforts to improve performance, functionality, and usability ensuring optimal user experience.

## **Fullstack Developer**

Freelance

October 2023 - January 2024

· Collaborated with a freelancer to develop "Deal-It," a web application revolutionizing negotiation by connecting users with proficient negotiators.

#### **Fullstack Intern**

**Colossal Innovations** 

July 2023 - October 2023, Islamabad

- · Spearheaded the design and development of a dynamic website for Colossal Innovations.
- · Engineered a robust administrative dashboard.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering**

Iqra University, Islamabad Campus • H-9, Islamabad • 2024 • 3.8 CGPA

## **Intermediate in Computer Science**

Islamabad Model College for Boys • F-10/4, Islamabad • 2020

# **Secondary School Certificate**

Islamabad Model College for Boys • G-11/1, Islamabad • 2018

## **PROJECTS**

#### **PlaySense**

Final-year project • playsense.netlify.app/

• PlaySense is a MERN stack project for eSports enthusiasts. Collaborate, receive coaching, input match data, and access advanced analytics for performance improvement. Empowering users to enhance eSports skills and foster a vibrant gaming community.

# Deal-It

Freelance • deal-it.vercel.app/

 Deal-It is transforming negotiation by connecting users with skilled negotiators, fostering seamless price discussions across tasks for an enhanced and simplified process.

## **Colossal Innovations Website**

Colossal Innovations • colossal-innovations.netlify.app/

Designed and developed a compelling website for Colossal Innovations, seamlessly presenting a diverse array of content such as blogs, careers, and
portfolio projects.

#### **Colossal Innovations Dashboard**

Colossal Innovations • colossal-innovations-dashboard.netlify.app/

• Dashboard with advanced role management for streamlined handling of blogs, careers, projects, website management, and centralized job applications.

# **SKILLS**

Fullstack Development, MERN Stack, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, Git, APIs, NextJS, Tailwindcss, Material UI, Mantine, Responsive Design.